# Tauseef Ibne Mamun

tmamun@mtu.edu +1 (857)-574-9931 https://tmamun.netlify.app

407 Shelden Avenue, Apt 9, Houghton, Michigan, 49931

# **SUMMARY**

Ph.D. student with specialized training in both human-computer interaction and behavioral psychology. Have a strong programming background. Experience in advanced-level human factors engineering (qualitative and quantitative) and executing usability studies mainly in software and rail warning systems.

### Research Tools/Methods

- Behavioral studies with human subjects
- Usability Evaluation in both real-time and simulated environments (eye-tracking, driving simulator, in-vehicle systems)
- Cognitive Task Analysis (CTA)
- Computational modeling
- Software development
- Development of R libraries for data management and interpretation

# **EDUCATION**

Michigan Technological University | Houghton, MI

Ph.D. Applied Cognitive Science and Human Factors

Expected 2023

Michigan Technological University | Houghton, MI

**Artificial Intelligence in Healthcare Certificate** 

2021

Michigan Technological University | Houghton, MI

**MS Applied Cognitive Science and Human Factors** 

2019 - 2021

Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology | Dhaka, Bangladesh

**BS Computer Science & Engineering** 

2011 - 2015

# **EXPERIENCES**

Michigan Technological University, Cognitive and Learning Sciences | Houghton, MI

**Research Assistant** 2019 - Present

# Tasks:

- User behavior analysis in autonomous driving for user-centric explanations.
- Designing novel explanation methods for the human-AI teaming.
- Developing computational models for naturalistic decision-making scenarios.
- Behavioral analysis of drivers in rail crossings through mixed-method approach.
- Assessment of the usability of new in-vehicle systems in rail crossings.
  - **❖** Working/Worked with **Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency** and **Federal Railroad Administration** on different research projects.

Mighty Egg Technologies | Canada/Bangladesh

# **Programmer Analyst**

2015 - 2018

#### Tasks:

- Database Design & API development.
- Web and Mobile App Development.

# **Programming Expertise**

Digital Ocean, Heroku.

Software deployment in Amazon Web Service,

R, Python, C, C++, Java, PHP, Ruby, PEBL

Git: GitHub (https://github.com/tm012)

# FEATURED LEADERSHIP ROLES

- Vice President at Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology's Computer Science & Engineering Society 2014 –
- Vice President at Bangladeshi Student Association at Michigan Technological University

2020 - 2021

### **INTERESTS**